

Yohanes Egi Pratama Yudo Utomo

August 26, 2000 | Lampung, Indonesia | Phone: 0895380277555

Email: yohanesegipratama@gmail.com

Linkedln: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yohanesegipratamayudoutomo

Github : https://github.com/hanesegi

SUMMARY

I am a fresh graduate of informatics engineering from the Indonesian Technocrat University Lampung, I am an outstanding student in 2021. I have teaching and research experience. I have been teaching elementary students for 5 months and I presented my research twice at International Conferences in ICSECC 2021 and ICE3IS 2022. I have Data Scientist and Data Analyst skills by following Algorithm Bootcamp in 4 months with score 124 out of 140 .. I have skills good communication and interpersonal skills, can operate Microsoft Office, and familiar with creating dashboards or reports using pivot, Tableau , and creating machine learning models. I have opportunity to work as data analyst/scientist.

EDUCATION

Universitas Teknokrat Indonesia

Bandar Lampung

Informatics

August 2019 - Present

• Current GPA: 3.89.

• 1st place Academic Expo in the field of data mining 2021 | Indonesian Technokrat University.

• ROV national 3rd place winner, | Technogine Telkom University (November 2020).

Algoritma Data Science School

Bandar Lampung

Full Stack Data Science

September - December 2022

• **Final Score**: 126/140.

• Capstone Project: Cyberbullying Sentiment Analysis using the Naive Bayes method.

EXPERIENCE

Algoritma Data Science School

Bandar Lampung

Campus Ambassador

Desember 2021 – Desember 2022

The Data Science School Algorithm Program in the form of an online scholarship bootcamp worth 8 billion

- Full stack data science scholarship recipients, studying for 4 months mastering 3 specializations namely: Data Analytics Specialization, Data Visualization Specialization and Machine Learning Specialization
- Share content and events hosted by Algoritma Data Science School on Linkedln or other social media,
 managed to collect 4870 points, became the Ambassador of The Month July

Amartha Bandar Lampung

Campus Ambassador

Maret – Juni 2022

Program from Amartha in making a big impact on the lives of others.

• Participate in designing campaign marketing boosters for corporate social responsibility projects. The Amartha Scholars Scholarship targeted 1,000 applicants and succeeded in getting 1,224 applicants.

Bisa Ai Academy

Bandar Lampung

Independent Study Program

Januari – Agustus 2022

It is one of the Certified Independent Study activities from the Merdeka Campus.

- Participated in Data Science, NLP, Computer Vision learning classes.
- Presentation of material on Time Series Forecasting using the FBProphet method with 27 participants.
- Became the project capstone team leader, with 10 members, played the role of data scientist and back end in the project.

Campus Teaching

Bandar Lampung

Teacher Assistant and IT Support

Agustus 2021 – Desember 2021

One of the programs from the Merdeka Campus in improving literacy and numeracy as well as learning using technology.

- Teach and create a literacy and numeracy syllabus for use by elementary school students in grade 4.
- Being a speaker introducing the AKSI Application (Indonesian Student Competency Assessment) to the Teacher Council for 1 week, attended by 16 teachers and educators. managed to meet the target of 32 Lesson Hours (JP).
- Participating in activities at school, I generate ideas to create a reading corner program, create a school web blog.

ORGANIZATION

UKM Roboboat Teknokrat Chairman

Bandar Lampung

Januari 2021 – Desember 2022

- Made a work program for one year during Covid-19, succeeded in holding a Social Service program to an Orphanage. Implemented Acceptance of new members, succeeded in adding 35 new members, Successfully sent 1 Team to pass the 2021 KKCTBN competition selection.
- Held training on writing competition proposals in preparation for the KKCTBN competition, attended by 28 members from all divisions.

UKM Teknokrat English Club

Bandar Lampung

Januari – Desember 2020

Member

• Actively participates in Scrabble competitions at the National level.

• Assist the head of the scrabble division in carrying out routine training every Saturday

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Digital Talent Scholarship Kominfo

Bandar Lampung

Data Engineer Student

September - December 2022

- Task completed include: SQL Querying, Programming Python, R
- Create Project: Simple ETL with Pandas

SKILLS AND LANGUAGES

 Hard Skill : Programming (Python, R SQL), Microsoft Office, Looker Studio, Tableau

Soft Skill : Communication, Problem Solving, Time Management, Adaption

Language Skill : Bahasa Indonesia: Native (spoken and written), English: Beginner

PORTOFOLIO

Sentiment Analysis Of Digital Wallet Users Reviews On Instagram Using SVM-RFE Method https://github.com/hanesegi/Analisis-Sentiment-Dompet-Digital---SVM-RFE

- Class labeling using Pretrain Transformer Roberta, Feature selection using Recursive Feature Elimination (RFE), and Modeling using SVM
- By using python, the model successfully performs classification with an accuracy value of 91%

Customer Churn Prediction using Logistic Regression, Random Forest, Xgboost https://github.com/hanesegi/Churn-Prediction-Using-LR-RF-XGB-

- Predict Churn using Logistic regression Algorithm, Random Forest and XGBoost compare the results
- By comparing the 3 algorithms created using the Python programming language, it is known that the XGBoost algorithm produces the best accuracy of 85%.

Cyberbullying Sentiment Analysis using the Naive Bayes method.

Confident Data

- Capstone Project for Machine Learning Specialization
- Classify sentiments that contain the meaning of bullying or not